(upbeat music)
- Hello, English learners.
Welcome back to EnglishPod.
My name is Marco.
- And I'm Erica.
- And today we're gonna be bringing you
a great lesson about calling the office.
- Yeah, that's right.
So in this lesson, we're going
to teach you some great words
that you can use when you need
to call your office to solve a problem.
- Right, so you are at home, you have a
problem, maybe you can't go to the office.
So you have to call them and tell them
that you're not gonna be able to go.
- Yes.
- All right, so we're not
gonna preview anything
today because the
dialogue is relatively easy.
So let's listen to the
dialogue for the first time
and then we'll come back
and look at some words.
(upbeat music)
- Hello, hey, annual date you can stay.
(speaking in foreign language)
- I hate annual day.
I hate annual day, I hate annual day.
- Actually, I'm eating
fake, I quit, I'll do today.
- I'm already say, I'll
eat your hay at day.
- That was hungry.
- I hate day, I'm, I'm in K, I'm on day,
it's a hote loo-fay.
I have a headache, or
say hote, ani-ray, o's nay,
and I'm eating fake, like
Lee say, you're first fay.
- I say, o's say, or yay, all in K and X-A.
- S-Y-A, I as way, open
hay, utte ette, offte.
- Ikuri-ray.
- Okay, and they, I tray
and at gay, I'm saying, I stray.
- All right, so a pretty
easy dialogue, right?
- Yeah, pretty simple.
- All right, so there are a couple of words
that we wanna look at, so let's
start with language takeaway.
- Language takeaway.
- All right, well today we're
looking at three interesting words.
The first one is oof-lay,
oof-lay, oof-lay, oof-lay.
Marco, what is the oof-lay?
- All right, so when you have the oof-lay,
it means that you are sick, you
have, it's very similar to a cold.
- Right, but just worse, right?
- Worse, yeah, so when
you have the oof-lay,
it'll keep you in bed for a
while, for maybe a week or two.
- So you have a fever,
your body is hurting.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- You're really sick.
- Yeah, you're really sick.
- Okay, so oof-lay.
- All right, well, what
about our next word?
- Well, actually the next word is a phrase
that you can use when
you're calling the office.
I'll incur in ixe.
- I'll incur in ixe.
- Okay, this is a really useful phrase,
and I think it would help
us to hear some examples
of what it sounds like, so we
can understand the meaning.
- Example one.
- Oof-lay, people pay an ixe with a tay.
- Example two.
- If oof-lay, all k in ixe, on one
or may I and tay, or yay, Iardfay.
- Example three.
- I'm not an ailing fail away.
- I'll say, I'm ailing k in ixe.
- So with this phrase, you're basically
saying that you are not going to the office.
- Exactly.
So let's take a look at our last
word for language takeaway.
- E-cover-ray.
Okay, so it's a pretty simple word.
E-cover-ray means-- - To get
better, to start feeling healthy again.
- Okay, so kind of to
recharge your batteries.
Exactly, so this is a great
verb to use when you want
to say I'm going to feel
better. Okay, you cover a
So some really great words
some really interesting phrases.
So let's listen to this dialogue
again, and then we'll come back
Hello, hey annual date you can
say I'll hey, hey, I help hey, we a I
Hey, alday, we date your hey, I hate ui j
Hey, I'll hey, are you yeah? Actually,
I'm eating fake I quit a lute today.
I'm already say it
would say ear hey at the
That was hungry. I
Hintay, I'm I'm in K.
On day it's a hote lueve
I have hey Eddie hey
or say hote on a ray.
Oh, it's me and I'm
eating fail. I at least say it's
You first fe I say I was
say or yay, I'll in K in x a
S yay, I as way open. Hey
Ete off a
Curie ray
Okay, and they I trade
and at gay I'm saying astray
All right, Michael have you ever found
yourself in a situation like this? Well
Yeah, a couple of times that I haven't
been able to really make it to the office
And I've had to call so
yeah, I would have to call
and tell them that I'm not
gonna make it or maybe then
I'm gonna be a
little bit late. All right.
Well, yeah, happens to all of us and
now you guys have all of this useful
Language next time you
face this problem exactly
So if you have any questions or comments
be sure to visit our website englishpot.com
Marco and I are there to respond to
your questions and comments as well
There are also lots of other great
lessons for you to check out on the website
Exactly, so be sure to check
out some of our first lessons.
I'm sure you'll find
them useful as well. Yes
Okay, well, thanks for listening
everyone and until next time